Finding Aid for the Colin Higgins papers, ca. 1960-1987 LSC.1560
UCLA Library Special Collections
Colin Higgins papers
ca. 1960-1987
UCLA Library Special Collections
Higgins, Colin
LSC.1560
73.5 Linear Feet (147 boxes)
2 oversize_folders
Colin Higgins (1941-1988) was a screenwriter and director of the film comedies Harold and Maude, Silver Streak, Foul Play, and Nine to Five. The collection consists of personal and professional correspondence, screenplays in various drafts, research materials, production reports, army and college notes, and photographs.
Restrictions on Access
Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Colin Higgins 1988 Trust, bequest, 1988.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9917204473606533
Biography
Higgins was born in Noumea, New Caledonia on July 28, 1941; attended Sorbonne, University of Paris, 1965; BA, Stanford, 1967; MFA, UCLA, 1970; screenwriter and director of film comedies Harold and Maude, Silver Streak, Foul Play, and Nine to Five; his film, Harold and Maude, was based on a screenplay written for his master's thesis; died on August 5, 1988.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of papers of Colin Higgins Productions, including personal and professional correspondence, screenplays in various drafts, research materials, production reports, army and college notes, and photographs.
Items Removed from Collection
The following film reels have been transferred to the UCLA Film and Television Archive.
Nine to Five, 6 reels.
Nine to Five, reels 1-3; [in box].
Nine to Five, reduction of reels 3-4.
Opus One.
Retreat.
Silver Streak, promo.
Best Little Whorehouse in Texas.
Best Little Whorehouse in Texas, gag reel.
The Devil's Daughter, part 1.
The Devil's Daughter, part 2.
Best Little Whorehouse in Texas, gag reel 3:1 xfer, TRK head.
Harold and Maude, 139, Colin Higgins #273-6769.
Best Little Whorehouse in Texas [in box].
Foul Play, Colin Higgins' personal copy.
35mm test of Harold and Maude.
Screenplays; Screenwriters -- Archives.; Motion picture producers and directors -- Archives.; Higgins, Colin, 1941-1988--Archives.
- A Long Day in a Short Year
  - [A Long Day in a Short Year, script; Typescript with holograph corrections]. (Box 135, Folder 13)
- A Man Who...
  - [A Man Who, script]. (Box 130, Folder 1)
- Another Hero
  - [Another Hero, short story(?)]. (Box 135, Folder 18)
- Army
  - [2d infantry division - correspondence, clippings, orders.]. (Box 136, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Army discharge. (Box 137, Folder 8)
  - [U.S. Army records - duty transfers, etc]. (Box 137, Folder 10)
  - [8th Infantry Division newspapers]. (Box 141, Folder 5)
- Battle of the Wizards
  - Partial screenplay and notes. (Box 59, Folder 12)
- Best Little Whorehouse in Texas
  - [Set designs, 2 items]. (Box Unknown container 216 for instance of [Set designs, 2 items]., Folder 1)
  - [Best Little Whorehouse in Texas, 7 posters]. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - [Set plan, 1 item]. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - [Set designs, 9 items]. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Actors for consideration. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Advertising. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Ad/pub weekly reports. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Opening ad. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Award nominations. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Budget. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Call sheets (location). (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Call sheets (at Universal). (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Casting. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Location cast list with deal information. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Character lists. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Cast deal memos. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Staff and crew lists. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Crew deals. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Cast and crew gifts. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - One line continuity. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Day out of days. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Deals. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Earnings. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Editing breakdown. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Editorial schedules and names of editors and phone #s. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Gag reel. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Legal. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Limericks. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Locations. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Looping lines. (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Maps, memorabilia. (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous expenses. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Piano sheet music. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Music submitted unsolicited. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Music. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Music lyrics, changes, etc. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Narration. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Narration and lyrics. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Football announcer sequence. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Personal notes to Colin Higgins. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - C. Higgins: Personal notes, New Zealand, 1982. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - C. Higgins: Personal notes, etc. - Australia (2 folders)., 1982 (Box 18, Folder 1, 2)
  - Production photographs. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Cast photographs - [empty]. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Casting photographs - 4 envelopes; Chicken ranch girls and backups, doggettes, aggies. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Photographs ordered for Colin Higgins. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Play - final draft - revised, February 23, 1978. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Play. Revised; With pencilled notes., February 23, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Play. Revised 2 copies., February 23, 1978. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Shooting and Post-production schedule. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Post-production. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Premiere - Austin, Texas., July 11, 1982. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Pre-production. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Previews. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Production boards and script breakdowns. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Production notes. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Production reports (at Universal). (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Production reports (location). (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Program from the play. (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Program from the film. (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Promotions. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Props. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Deauville Film Festival clippings. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Press clippings - prior to opening. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Press kits - 2 items. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Australia - New Zealand press clippings. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Australia - New Zealand press clippings #2. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Press clippings from Texas location. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Press clippings from Texas location #2. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Publicity. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Interviews - Colin Higgins. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - MPAA rating. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - The Chicken Ranch book. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Research. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Theodora Van Runkel interview. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Colin Higgins - backup research. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Dolly Parton interviews. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Texas Monthly article. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Interview with Sheriff Jim Boutwell. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Playboy article. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Universal's residuals list. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Reviews (3 folders). (Box 22, Folder 5-7)
  - Screenings. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - King Masterson draft, - First draft screenplay; 2 copies., July 17, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - King Masterson draft,; 2 copies., April 24, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Early notes, December 1980 and January 1981. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Author's outline with notes, January 1981. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Outline, February 1, 1981. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Revisions, February 16, 1981. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Outline, February 24, 1981. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Script,; 3 copies. Brown cover - annotated., March 1, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Opening pages. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Draft, March 20, 1981. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Draft with revised opening and 2 songs, March 20, 1928. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - File copy - annotated. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Draft for final screenplay, April 14, 1981. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Final draft screenplay,; 3 copies., April 14, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Notes on script in progress. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Drafts for revised final, August 21, 1981. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Drafts for revised final,; 2 copies., August 21, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Revised final draft screenplay. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Revised final draft screenplay, August 21, 1981. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Revised final draft screenplay; With revised pages, September 14, 1981. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Revised final draft screenplay - covers only. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Final draft screenplay notes (2 folders). (Box 26, Folder 1, 2)
  - Suggestions for revised ending, April 28, 1982. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Script supervisor notes. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Script timing. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Sets. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Shooting schedule. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - One line shooting schedule. (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - 16mm. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Aggie Dance - storyboard (3 copies) and notes. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Texas has a whorehouse in it - storyboard,; 3 copies., September 11, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Texas has a whorehouse in it - introduction scene and musical #; With correspondence, July 28, 1981. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Melvin into fountain - storyboard,; 3 copies., July 28, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - The shag - storyboard [binder with notes]. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - The raid - storyboard,; 3 copies and notes., September 15, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - The sidestep - storyboard; 3 copies,; final,, n.d., June 24, 1981 September 24, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Hardcandy [Christmas] - storyboard. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Pissant - storyboard (part shot in Texas). (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Twenty fans - storyboard - 4 copies (2 folders); Early version,, new version - 2 part.., June 30, 1981 February 23, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 4, 5)
  - Storyboards - Tommy Tune. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Television version. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Commercial Television version. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Main and end titles. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Travel. (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Videocassette. (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Wardrobe. (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Westgate Feature Services. (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Writers Guild. (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Cassettes. (Box 29, Folder unknown container)
  - Doatsy Mae - Broadway Version. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - LTD - Ain't we a double, September 9, 1981. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - The Aggie song - Broadway Version. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Pissant - Dolly. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - The side step - Broadway Version. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - GTDY - Where stallions run, PTDX - Sneakin'around., September 16, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Aggie song and dance, July 28, 1981. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Dolly Parton, - Dolby - [7 songs]., September 1981 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Sidestep - revisited. (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Dolly Parton, - [3 songs on casssette]., February 25, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Sweel loving friends - recorded in Nashville; With 5 other songs on cassette., July 20 - June 22 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Dolly Parton, [4 songs on cassette]., April 30, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - A gamble either way - Dolly - Nashville, August 2, 1981. (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - GTDX - Where stallions run - rehearsal cassette, September 9, 1981. (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Soliloquy - revisions - Charles Fox and Norman Gimble., August 6, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Dolly Parton and Burt Reynolds - Rough mixes; 3 songs on cassettes., August 18-20, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - CTD sidestep - Part 1 and 2 - rehearsal,; Texas has a whorehouse - Dom Deluise, September 14, 1981 October 13, 1981. (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - FTDX - Twenty fans - new piano ragtime, December 7, 1981. (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Soliloquy - 1st, 2nd alternates - piano tracks. (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Texas has a whorehouse - Broadway. (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - HTDZ - I will always love you - Dolly's new vocal, December 13, 1981. (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - KTDXY, - Hard candy Christmas., December 31, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - GTDX - Where stallions run, - revision., September 17/18 (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Hard Candy Christmas - Broadway Version. (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - Hard Candy Christmas - Broadway Version. (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - Soliloquy - revised, August 6, 1981. (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Cassettes. (Box 30, Folder unknown container)
  - Soliloquy - 1st and 2nd alternate tracks - piano tracks. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Soliloquy - revised, August 6, 1981. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Ballad - - short version - scratch mix, January 8, 1982. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Burt's soliloquy, August 3, 1981. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Burt's soliloquy, August 3, 1981. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Burt's soliloquy, August 3, 1981. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Pissant - Dolly Parton - Nashville, August 21, 1981. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Hard Candy Christmas - Dolly - long instrumental introduction, August 2, 1981. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Hard Candy Christmas - Dolly - short introduction, August 2, 1981. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Hard Candy Christmas - Dolly - long introduction, August 21, 1981. (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Girl you're a woman - Dolly - Nashville with chorus., August 2, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Bus to Amarilla - Dolly - Nashville, August 2, 1981. (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Twenty fans - Broadway. (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Twenty fans, August 28 [August 31?]. (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Twenty fans - August 21 - version A and B. (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Twenty fans - August 31. (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - FTDX - Twenty fans - new piano ragtime, December 7, 1981. (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - KTD - Hard Candy Christmas - rehearsal cassette, September 9, 1981. (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - DTD - sidestep - reprise - rehearsal cassette., September 14, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - ATD - Aggie song and dance, - rehearsal cassette., September 13, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - KZTD - Hard Candy Christmas - long introduction - no instrumental, September 11, 1981. (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - PTDX - Sneakin' around, - revision., September 17, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - BTD - Courtyard shag - rehearsal cassette, September 14, 1981. (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Girl you're a woman - Dolly - Nashville - no chorus., August 2, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Pissant country place - Dolly Parton - 6:40. (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Cassettes. (Box 31, Folder unknown container)
  - First pitch on whorehouse, - Tom Miller's apartment., January 27, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Burt songs - Whorehouse. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - HTS - I will always love you - rehearsal cassette, September 7, 1981. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Piano. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - RTDZ - I will always love you - Dolly's new vocal, December 13, 1981. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - BLWT - all songs, July 1, 1981. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Duets. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - QTD - A gamble either way - rehearsal cassette, September 9, 1981. (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - HTD - I will always love you - rehearsal cassette, September 17, 1981. (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - I wish I were a poet - a gamble either way - July 27, 1981. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Don't do me no favor. (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - She's a good old girl [and 9 other songs]. (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Texas. (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - BLWIT - What we're doing nows, got nothing to do with love. (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - BLWIT - Give me no answer. (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Ida Red. (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - What we're doin' now's ... - Snuff Garrett, May 21, 1981. (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Twenty fans - demo, May 23, 1981. (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - KXTD - Hard Candy Christmas,; Minus 1st chorus, instrumental turn around and 2nd verse., September 11, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - NXTD - Texas has a whorehouse in it,; #2, oddball lyric., September 14, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - NTD Texas has a whorehouse in it - reprise #2,; Straight lyric., September 14, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - JTD - Pissant - rehearsal cassette, September 8, 1981. (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - MTD - Texas has a whorehouse in it - reprise #1,; Rehearsal cassette., September 14, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - FTD - Twenty fans, - rehearsal cassette - 5:23., September 14, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Twenty fans - Richard Baskin, July 15, 1981. (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Twenty fans - piano/vocal, May 26, 1981. (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Cassettes. (Box 32, Folder unknown container)
  - I wish I'd been a poet - Burt Reynolds, July 13, 1981. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - ETD part 1,2,3 - Texas has a whorehouse, - rehearsal., September 14, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - GTDX - Where stallions run, - revisions., September 17, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - PTD - sneakin' around - rehearsal cassette, September 9, 1981. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - KTD - Hard Candy Christmas - rehearsal cassette, September 9, 1981. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - KYTD - Hard Candy Christmas - a short introduction,; No instrumental., September 11, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Twenty fans - revisions, June 18, 1981. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Twenty fans - version C - August 21. (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Twenty fans, - w/20's speed, w/o 20's speed; With vocal cito(?)., July 1, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - [Bound volume of prduction stills]. (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - [Best Little Whorehouse in Texas, costume slides, Dolly P.]. (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - [Best Little Whorehouse in Texas final draft screenplay];, no.52, with corrections., August 21, 1981 (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - [Best Little Whorehouse in Texas, shooting schedule]. (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - [Best Little Whorehouse in Texas - lobby cards]. (Box 141, Folder 7)
  - [The Best Little Whorehouse in Texas, scrapbook]. (Box 143, Folder 1)
  - [The Best Little Whorehouse in Texas, scrapbook]. (Box 143, Folder 2)
  - Photographs - 21 items (10 folders). (Box 146, Folder 12-21)
  - Laser video disk. (Box 147, Folder 1)
- Biography
  - Colin Higgins biography. (Box 112, Folder 1)
- Blue Bird
  - [The blue bird, final draft of shooting script, August 1975]. (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - [The blue bird, latest, March 21, 1974]. (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - [The blue bird, hand written script]. (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - [The blue bird script]. (Box 127, Folder 4)
  - [The blue bird, unbound script]. (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Kate Hepburn's script for The Bluebird. (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - [The blue bird, research notes and film fragment]. (Box 127, Folder 7)
- Bogart Slept Here
  - Screenplay by Neil Simon. 2nd rev., - #2., July 6-August 28, 1975 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Screenplay by Neil Simon - third draft, November 1975. (Box 55, Folder 5)
- Books
  - [The George Cukor collection, George Houle, Los Angeles: ]; Signed by the authors of the forward, except C. Higgins., 1986 (Box 109, Folder 3)
- Calamity Man
  - [The Calamity Man script, September 5, 1972]. (Box 129, Folder 9)
- California Suite
  - Screenplay by Neil Simon - 1st draft, May 1977. (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Screenplay by Neil Simon - 3rd draft, January 1978. (Box 55, Folder 7)
- Canterbury Tales
  - [Canterbury tales - clipings, correspondence, notes, etc.]. (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - [Canterbury tales, first treatment. (Box 130, Folder 3)
  - [God, the clergy, and Harry Bailly - paper by C. Higgins]. (Box 130, Folder 4)
  - [Canterbury tales, screenplay]. (Box 130, Folder 5)
  - [God, the clergy, and Harry Bailly - paper by C. Higgins, A+]. (Box 130, Folder 6)
  - [Canterbury tales, a first treatment]. (Box 130, Folder 7)
  - [Canterbury tales screenplay]. (Box 130, Folder 8)
- Charlotte, Slut of the South
  - Screenplay by Howard Franklin - revisions draft, September 26, 1984. (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Screenplay by Howard Franklin - revisions draft, September 26, 1984. (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Screenplay by Howard Franklin - revised draft, September 26, 1984. (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Screenplay by Howard Franklin - revised draft, September 17, 1984. (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - [Notes], 1983, 1984. (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Partial versions scripts, July 19, July 26 and August 7, 1984, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - [Notes for the trailer],; With romance novel greeting cards., July 13, 1984 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Jezabel, July 11, 1984. (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Final treatment for revised draft,; With earlier drafts, notes for third act., July 19, 1984 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Treatment of Howard Franklin's screenplay and 1st draft; With notes on Beulah Land.., June and July 1984. (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - [Production script - annotated by Higgins]. (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Boy from Montana. (Box 75, Folder 18)
  - [Notes, memos]. (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Deal memo. (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Scripts. (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Notes - James Cass Rogers. (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Scripts, June 1984. (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Scripts, September 4, 1984. (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Scripts, September 17, 1984. (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Scripts, September 26, 1984. (Box 76, Folder 7)
- Chaucer
  - [Chaucer screenplay]. (Box 138, Folder 1)
  - [Chaucer, research materials]. (Box 138, Folder 3)
  - [Chaucer, research materials]. (Box 138, Folder 4)
- Cheap Detective
  - First draft - screenplay by Neil Simon. (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Final draft- screenplay by Neil Simon, - #71., February 28, 1977 (Box 55, Folder 2)
- Christ Film
  - [Christ film]. (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - [Christ film - scrapbook on Christ's life]. (Box 134, Folder 3)
- Clark Gable Slept Here
  - Screenplay by Neil Simon, September 1974. (Box 55, Folder 3)
- Clippings
  - Interesting clippings. (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous clippings. (Box 112, Folder 6)
  - [Newspapers, magazines, clippings, promotional material]. (Box 140, Folder 1)
- Colin Higgins - Personal
  - [Notes - work in progress]. (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - [Writing paper and Los Angeles Times Home Magazine, September 8, 1985]. (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Hugh O'Brien awards. (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - [Story ideas, personal cards, ephemera]. (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Colin's bulletin board. (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Writers. (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - [Miscellaneous]. (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - Biography, 1982. (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Charity contributions, [empty]., 1988 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, [empty]., 1988 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, [empty]., 1988 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Thoughts on people and events. (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences. (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Accidents / Break-ins. (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Dennis Adams. (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - AGA awards. (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - American Cinematheque. (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - American Film Institute - Advisory Committee. (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - American Film Institute. (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Association for Humanistic Psychology. (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - Mel Blanc - fifty years. (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - Blue Fish Cove. (Box 64, Folder 15)
  - Inventory - offfice bookshelves. (Box 64, Folder 16)
  - Cardholders action line. (Box 64, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1987. (Box 64, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1986. (Box 64, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1985. (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1984. (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1983. (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1982. (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1981. (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1980. (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1979. (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1978. (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1977. (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Diet and health (Brugh Joy Conference, )., October 16-October 30, 1983 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Diet and health. (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Directors Guild of America (2 folders). (Box 66, Folder 5, 6)
  - Drivers - tests, school, tickets, etc. (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - [Star Magazine, October 15, 1985]. (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Nicholas Eliopoulos. (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Findhorn. (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - George Gelles. (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Samuel Goldwyn awards. (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Ruth Gordon. (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - Someone to tell it to. (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Public image (Ruth Gordon). (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - Happy Days Hollywood Reporter. (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - Hay Foundation. (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Hirsch, Barry (Armstrong, Hirsch and Levine). (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Insight. (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Speaking engagements / interviews, 1987. (Box 67, Folder 4)